Joseph Post

Curious engineer with an eye for innovation and excellence. Has five years of experience in oversight of various Department of Defense instrumentation and control (I&C) equipment software, resulting in a total software development cost savings of \$2.5M. Has lead product development and managed the qualification, integration, and configuration of multiple I&C components, both custom-built and commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS).

Experience

Naval Reactors Engineer - Naval Sea Systems Command

Jul 2014 – Present

- Oversees the design and development of GERALD R. FORD (CVN 78) Class propulsion plant I&C, including workstations, network cabinets, and field devices such as motor controllers, sensors/detectors, and chlorinators.
- Ensures that these I&C components meet all applicable military specifications
- Manages and leads real- and near-real time troubleshooting of instrumentation and control issues aboard CVN 78 and JOHN F. KENNEDY (CVN 79), as well as approve equipment requirements for ENTERPRISE (CVN 80).

Integrated Circuit (IC) Layout Engineer Co-op – Synaptics

Nov 2012 - May 2013

- Created custom layout for circuitry within touch/display drivers used in a multiple smartphones.
- Updated previous layouts due to schematic changes and verify layouts using Layout vs. Schematic and Design Rule Checking software.
- Identified electrostatic discharge needs and followed designer requirements while maintaining minimum area requirements for more efficient designs.
- Created tightly packed, symmetric IC layout for operational amplifier used in various Samsung smartphones.

Electrical Engineering Co-op – Ultra Electronics - Flightline Systems

Nov 2011 - Mar 2012

- Designed and constructed test fixture for radio module used in Naval sonobuoys.
- Researched technical specifications provided by the military and choose and/or design circuit parameters and parts that are most space and power efficient.
- Created digital timing diagrams and perform timing verification tests, as well as produce appropriate schematics for fixtures.

Education

Masters of Science in Engineering Science (MSES) - Naval Postgraduate School

Sep 2014 – May 2017

Focused heavily in computer architecture with coursework in digital signal processing and advanced networks.

Bachelors of Science (BSEE) - Rochester Institute of Technology

Sep 2009 – May 2014

Focused in various electrical engineering subject such as computer architecture, power electronics, mechatronics, and radio frequency applications.

Licenses

Engineer in Training in the State of Virginia. NCEES ID: 18-271-80

Projects

See Github account for detailed list and description of projects.

Personal Info

Email

jpost625@gmail.com

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/josephpost-a5481b28/

Github

https://github.com/poster515

C

Skills

Project Management ●●● expert VHDL.

expert

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$ Modelsim advanced

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$

advanced

....

.... Python intermediate

•••00 MATLAB intermediate

SQL advanced

Tech Communication ● ● ● ● expert

.... Microsoft Office advanced

Hobbies

- Fitness (weightlifting, running)
- Disc golfing
- Programming
- Camping and Cooking